<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <entry>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1609.09166v2</id>
        <updated>2017-01-10T19:29:23Z</updated>
        <published>2016-09-29T01:36:42Z</published>
        <title>Quantum simulation of driven para-Bose oscillators</title>
        <summary>
            Quantum mechanics allows paraparticles with mixed Bose-Fermi statistics that
            have not been experimentally confirmed. We propose a trapped-ion scheme whose
            effective dynamics are equivalent to a driven para-Bose oscillator of even
            order. Our mapping suggest highly entangled vibrational and internal ion states
            as the laboratory equivalent of quantum simulated parabosons. Furthermore, we
            show the generation and reconstruction of coherent oscillations and para-Bose
            analogs of Gilmore-Perelomov coherent states from population inversion
            measurements in the laboratory frame. Our proposal, apart from demonstrating an
            analog quantum simulator of para-Bose oscillators, provides a quantum state
            engineering tool that foreshadows the potential use of paraparticle dynamics in
            the design of quantum information systems.
        </summary>
        <author>
            <name>C. Huerta Alderete</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>B. M. Rodríguez-Lara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1701.02683v1</id>
        <updated>2017-01-10T16:52:17Z</updated>
        <published>2017-01-10T16:52:17Z</published>
        <title>Recovering the ideal results of a perturbed analog quantum simulator</title>
        <summary>
            Well controlled quantum systems can potentially be used as quantum
            simulators. However a quantum simulator is inevitably perturbed by coupling to
            additional degrees of freedom. This constitutes a major roadblock to useful
            quantum simulations. So far there are only limited means to understand the
            effect of perturbation on the results of quantum simulation. Here, we present a
            method, which in certain circumstances, allows for the reconstruction of the
            ideal result from measurements on a perturbed quantum simulator. We consider
            extracting the value of correlator $\langle\hat{O}^i(t) \hat{O}^j(0)\rangle$
            from the simulated system, where $\hat{O}^i$ are the operators which couple the
            system to its environment. The ideal correlator can be straightforwardly
            reconstructed by using statistical knowledge of the environment, if any
            $n$-time correlator of operators $\hat{O}^i$ of the ideal system can be written
            as products of two-time correlators. We give an approach to verify the validity
            of this assumption experimentally by additional measurements on the perturbed
            quantum simulator. The proposed method can allow for reliable quantum
            simulations with systems subjected to environmental noise without adding an
            overhead to the quantum system.
        </summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iris Schwenk</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Jan-Michael Reiner</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Sebastian Zanker</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Lin Tian</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Juha Leppäkangas</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Marthaler</name>
        </author>
      
    </entry>  
</feed>
